<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/vindex/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/vindex/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-26T18:37:20+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vindex/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Vindex Cycling Club</title><subtitle>Vindex Cycling Club</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Ghost</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vindex/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Ghost" /><published>2017-07-27T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vindex/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vindex/welcome"><![CDATA[<p>Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)</p>

<p>We know that first impressions are important, so we’ve populated your new site with some initial <strong>Getting Started</strong> posts that will help you get familiar with everything in no time. This is the first one!</p>

<h3 id="there-are-a-few-things-that-you-should-know-up-front">There are a few things that you should know up-front:</h3>
<ol>
  <li>Ghost is designed for ambitious, professional publishers who want to actively build a business around their content. That’s who it works best for. If you’re using Ghost for some other purpose, that’s fine too - but it might not be the best choice for you.</li>
  <li>The entire platform can be modified and customized to suit your needs, which is very powerful, but doing so <strong>does</strong> require some knowledge of code. Ghost is not necessarily a good platform for beginners or people who just want a simple personal blog.</li>
  <li>For the best experience we recommend downloading the Ghost Desktop App for your computer, which is the best way to access your Ghost site on a desktop device.</li>
</ol>

<p>Ghost is made by an independent non-profit organisation called the Ghost Foundation. We are 100% self funded by revenue from our <a href="https://ghost.org/pricing">Ghost(Pro)</a> service, and every penny we make is re-invested into funding further development of free, open source technology for modern journalism.</p>

<p>The main thing you’ll want to read about next is probably: <a href="https://demo.ghost.io/the-editor/">the Ghost editor</a>.</p>

<p>Once you’re done reading, you can simply delete the default <strong>Ghost</strong> user from your team to remove all of these introductory posts!</p>]]></content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using the Ghost editor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vindex/the-editor" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using the Ghost editor" /><published>2017-07-27T10:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T10:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vindex/the-editor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vindex/the-editor"><![CDATA[<p>Ghost uses a language called <strong>Markdown</strong> to format text.</p>
<p>When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause.</p>
<p>At the bottom of the editor, you'll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You'll also notice that there's a <strong>?</strong> icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts.</p>
<p>For now, though, let's run you through some of the basics. You'll want to make sure you're editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we've used.</p>
<h2 id="formattingtext">Formatting text</h2>
<p>The most common shortcuts are of course, <strong>bold</strong> text, <em>italic</em> text, and <a href="https://example.com">hyperlinks</a>. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts.</p>
<ul>
<li><code>CMD/Ctrl + B</code> for Bold</li>
<li><code>CMD/Ctrl + I</code> for Italic</li>
<li><code>CMD/Ctrl + K</code> for a Link</li>
<li><code>CMD/Ctrl + H</code> for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc)</li>
</ul>
<p>With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you're well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story.</p>
<h2 id="insertingimages">Inserting images</h2>
<p>Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they're prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this:</p>
<p><code>![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg)</code></p>
<p><img src="https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/computer.jpg" alt="Computer"></p>
<p>Most Markdown editors don't make you type this out, though. In Ghost you can click on the image icon in the toolbar at the bottom of the editor, or you can just click and drag an image from your desktop directly into the editor. Both will upload the image for you and generate the appropriate Markdown.</p>
<p><em><strong>Important Note:</strong> Ghost does not currently have automatic image resizing, so it's always a good idea to make sure your images aren't gigantic files <strong>before</strong> uploading them to Ghost.</em></p>
<h2 id="makinglists">Making lists</h2>
<p>Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use <code>*</code> or <code>-</code> or <code>+</code>. Like this:</p>
<ol>
<li>Crack the eggs over a bowl</li>
<li>Whisk them together</li>
<li>Make an omellete</li>
</ol>
<p>or</p>
<ul>
<li>Remember to buy milk</li>
<li>Feed the cat</li>
<li>Come up with idea for next story</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="addingquotes">Adding quotes</h2>
<p>When you want to pull out a particularly good except in the middle of a piece, you can use <code>&gt;</code> at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might've seen this formatting before in email clients.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made</p>
</blockquote>
<p>All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they'll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly.</p>
<h2 id="dividingthingsup">Dividing things up</h2>
<p>If you're writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping <code>---</code> on a new line will create a sleak divider, anywhere you want it.</p>
<hr>
<p>This should get you going with the vast majority of what you need to do in the editor, but if you're still curious about more advanced tips then check out the <a href="/advanced-markdown/">Advanced Markdown Guide</a> - or if you'd rather learn about how Ghost taxononomies work, we've got a overview of <a href="/using-tags/">how to use Ghost tags</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ghost uses a language called Markdown to format text. When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause. At the bottom of the editor, you'll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You'll also notice that there's a ? icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts. For now, though, let's run you through some of the basics. You'll want to make sure you're editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we've used. Formatting text The most common shortcuts are of course, bold text, italic text, and hyperlinks. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts. CMD/Ctrl + B for Bold CMD/Ctrl + I for Italic CMD/Ctrl + K for a Link CMD/Ctrl + H for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc) With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you're well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story. Inserting images Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they're prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this: ![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg) Most Markdown editors don't make you type this out, though. In Ghost you can click on the image icon in the toolbar at the bottom of the editor, or you can just click and drag an image from your desktop directly into the editor. Both will upload the image for you and generate the appropriate Markdown. Important Note: Ghost does not currently have automatic image resizing, so it's always a good idea to make sure your images aren't gigantic files before uploading them to Ghost. Making lists Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use * or - or +. Like this: Crack the eggs over a bowl Whisk them together Make an omellete or Remember to buy milk Feed the cat Come up with idea for next story Adding quotes When you want to pull out a particularly good except in the middle of a piece, you can use &gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might've seen this formatting before in email clients. A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they'll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly. Dividing things up If you're writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping --- on a new line will create a sleak divider, anywhere you want it. This should get you going with the vast majority of what you need to do in the editor, but if you're still curious about more advanced tips then check out the Advanced Markdown Guide - or if you'd rather learn about how Ghost taxononomies work, we've got a overview of how to use Ghost tags.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Organising your content with tags</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vindex/using-tags" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Organising your content with tags" /><published>2017-07-27T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vindex/using-tags</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vindex/using-tags"><![CDATA[<p>Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags.</p>
<p>It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content.</p>
<h2 id="basictagging">Basic tagging</h2>
<p>When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with <code>News</code> and other posts with <code>Cycling</code>, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on <code>/tag/news/</code> and <code>/tag/cycling/</code>, respectively.</p>
<p>If you tag a post with both <code>News</code> <em>and</em> <code>Cycling</code> - then it appears in both sections.</p>
<p>Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data.</p>
<h2 id="theprimarytag">The primary tag</h2>
<p>Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important.</p>
<p><mark><strong>News</strong>, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports</mark></p>
<p>In this example, <strong>News</strong> is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives.</p>
<h2 id="privatetags">Private tags</h2>
<p>Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling.</p>
<p>For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do.</p>
<p><mark><strong>News</strong>, Cycling, #video</mark></p>
<p>Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of <code>News</code>, and <code>Cycling</code> - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with <code>#video</code>.</p>
<p>In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting:</p>

<pre><code class="nohighlight">{{#post}}
    {{#has tag=&quot;#video&quot;}}
        ...markup for a nice big video post layout...
    {{else}}
        ...regular markup for a post...
    {{/has}}
{{/post}}
</code></pre>
<p>You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive <a href="https://themes.ghost.org/">theme documentation</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags. It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content. Basic tagging When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with News and other posts with Cycling, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on /tag/news/ and /tag/cycling/, respectively. If you tag a post with both News and Cycling - then it appears in both sections. Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data. The primary tag Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important. News, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports In this example, News is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives. Private tags Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling. For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do. News, Cycling, #video Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of News, and Cycling - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with #video. In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting: {{#post}} {{#has tag=&quot;#video&quot;}} ...markup for a nice big video post layout... {{else}} ...regular markup for a post... {{/has}} {{/post}} You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive theme documentation.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Managing Ghost users</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vindex/managing-users" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Managing Ghost users" /><published>2017-07-27T08:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T08:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vindex/managing-users</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vindex/managing-users"><![CDATA[<p>Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team</p>
<h3 id="authors">Authors</h3>
<p>The base user level in Ghost is an author. Authors can write posts, edit their own posts, and publish their own posts. Authors are <strong>trusted</strong> users. If you don't trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, you shouldn't invite them to Ghost admin.</p>
<h3 id="editors">Editors</h3>
<p>Editors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new authors to the site.</p>
<h3 id="administrators">Administrators</h3>
<p>The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site.</p>
<h3 id="theowner">The Owner</h3>
<p>There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable — for example, billing details, if using Ghost(Pro).</p>
<hr>
<p>It's a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team Authors The base user level in Ghost is an author. Authors can write posts, edit their own posts, and publish their own posts. Authors are trusted users. If you don't trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, you shouldn't invite them to Ghost admin. Editors Editors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new authors to the site. Administrators The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site. The Owner There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable — for example, billing details, if using Ghost(Pro). It's a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making your site private</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vindex/private-sites" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making your site private" /><published>2017-07-27T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vindex/private-sites</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vindex/private-sites"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes you might want to put your site behind closed doors</p>
<p>If you've got a publication that you don't want the world to see yet because it's not ready to launch, you can hide your Ghost site behind a simple shared pass-phrase.</p>
<p>You can toggle this preference on at the bottom of Ghost's General Settings</p>
<p><img src="https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/private.png" alt="private"></p>
<p>Ghost will give you a short, randomly generated pass-phrase which you can share with anyone who needs access to the site while you're working on it. While this setting is enabled, all search engine optimisation features will be switched off to help keep the site off the radar.</p>
<p>Do remember though, this is <em>not</em> secure authentication. You shouldn't rely on this feature for protecting important private data. It's just a simple, shared pass-phrase for very basic privacy.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes you might want to put your site behind closed doors If you've got a publication that you don't want the world to see yet because it's not ready to launch, you can hide your Ghost site behind a simple shared pass-phrase. You can toggle this preference on at the bottom of Ghost's General Settings Ghost will give you a short, randomly generated pass-phrase which you can share with anyone who needs access to the site while you're working on it. While this setting is enabled, all search engine optimisation features will be switched off to help keep the site off the radar. Do remember though, this is not secure authentication. You shouldn't rely on this feature for protecting important private data. It's just a simple, shared pass-phrase for very basic privacy.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Advanced Markdown tips</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vindex/advanced-markdown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advanced Markdown tips" /><published>2017-07-27T06:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T06:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vindex/advanced-markdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vindex/advanced-markdown"><![CDATA[<p>There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Ghost editor</p>
<p>If you've gotten pretty comfortable with <a href="/the-editor/">all the basics</a> of writing in Ghost, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!</p>
<p>As with the last post about the editor, you'll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we're using.</p>
<h2 id="specialformatting">Special formatting</h2>
<p>As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:</p>
<ul>
<li><s>strike through</s></li>
<li><mark>highlight</mark></li>
<li>*escaped characters*</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="writingcodeblocks">Writing code blocks</h2>
<p>There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, <code>like this</code>. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:</p>
<pre><code>.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
</code></pre>
<p>If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using <a href="http://prismjs.com/">Prism.js</a>.</p>
<h2 id="fullbleedimages">Full bleed images</h2>
<p>One neat trick which you can use in Markdown to distinguish between different types of images is to add a <code>#hash</code> value to the end of the source URL, and then target images containing the hash with special styling. For example:</p>
<p><img src="https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/walking.jpg#full" alt="walking"></p>
<p>which is styled with...</p>
<pre><code>img[src$=&quot;#full&quot;] {
    max-width: 100vw;
}
</code></pre>
<p>This creates full-bleed images in the Casper theme, which stretch beyond their usual boundaries right up to the edge of the window. Every theme handles these types of things slightly differently, but it's a great trick to play with if you want to have a variety of image sizes and styles.</p>
<h2 id="referencelists">Reference lists</h2>
<p><strong>The quick brown <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fox" title="Wikipedia: Fox">fox</a>, jumped over the lazy <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dog" title="Wikipedia: Dog">dog</a>.</strong></p>
<p>Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.</p>
<h2 id="creatingfootnotes">Creating footnotes</h2>
<p>The quick brown fox<sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1">[1]</a></sup> jumped over the lazy dog<sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn2" id="fnref2">[2]</a></sup>.</p>
<p>Footnotes are a great way to add additional contextual details when appropriate. Ghost will automatically add footnote content to the very end of your post.</p>
<h2 id="fullhtml">Full HTML</h2>
<p>Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you're never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Ghost editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here's a standard YouTube embed code as an example:</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<hr class="footnotes-sep">
<section class="footnotes">
<ol class="footnotes-list">
<li id="fn1" class="footnote-item"><p>Foxes are red <a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn2" class="footnote-item"><p>Dogs are usually not red <a href="#fnref2" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Ghost editor If you've gotten pretty comfortable with all the basics of writing in Ghost, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown! As with the last post about the editor, you'll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we're using. Special formatting As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example: strike through highlight *escaped characters* Writing code blocks There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, like this. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks: .my-link { text-decoration: underline; } If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Prism.js. Full bleed images One neat trick which you can use in Markdown to distinguish between different types of images is to add a #hash value to the end of the source URL, and then target images containing the hash with special styling. For example: which is styled with... img[src$=&quot;#full&quot;] { max-width: 100vw; } This creates full-bleed images in the Casper theme, which stretch beyond their usual boundaries right up to the edge of the window. Every theme handles these types of things slightly differently, but it's a great trick to play with if you want to have a variety of image sizes and styles. Reference lists The quick brown fox, jumped over the lazy dog. Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference. Creating footnotes The quick brown fox[1] jumped over the lazy dog[2]. Footnotes are a great way to add additional contextual details when appropriate. Ghost will automatically add footnote content to the very end of your post. Full HTML Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you're never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Ghost editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here's a standard YouTube embed code as an example: Foxes are red ↩︎ Dogs are usually not red ↩︎]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Setting up your own Ghost theme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vindex/themes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting up your own Ghost theme" /><published>2017-07-27T05:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T05:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vindex/themes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vindex/themes"><![CDATA[<p>Creating a totally custom design for your publication</p>
<p>Ghost comes with a beautiful default theme called Casper, which is designed to be a clean, readable publication layout and can be easily adapted for most purposes. However, Ghost can also be completely themed to suit your needs. Rather than just giving you a few basic settings which act as a poor proxy for code, we just let you write code.</p>
<p>There are a huge range of both free and premium pre-built themes which you can get from the <a href="http://marketplace.ghost.org">Ghost Theme Marketplace</a>, or you can simply create your own from scratch.</p>
<p><a href="http://marketplace.ghost.org"><img src="https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/marketplace.jpg" alt="marketplace"></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Anyone can write a completely custom Ghost theme, with just some solid knowledge of HTML and CSS</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ghost themes are written with a templating language called handlebars, which has a bunch of dynamic helpers to insert your data into template files. Like <code></code>, for example, outputs the name of the current author.</p>
<p>The best way to learn how to write your own Ghost theme is to have a look at <a href="https://github.com/TryGhost/Casper">the source code for Casper</a>, which is heavily commented and should give you a sense of how everything fits together.</p>
<ul>
<li><code>default.hbs</code> is the main template file, all contexts will load inside this file unless specifically told to use a different template.</li>
<li><code>post.hbs</code> is the file used in the context of viewing a post.</li>
<li><code>index.hbs</code> is the file used in the context of viewing the home page.</li>
<li>and so on</li>
</ul>
<p>We've got <a href="http://themes.ghost.org/docs/about">full and extensive theme documentation</a> which outlines every template file, context and helper that you can use.</p>
<p>If you want to chat with other people making Ghost themes to get any advice or help, there's also a <strong>#themes</strong> channel in our <a href="https://slack.ghost.org">public Slack community</a> which we always recommend joining!</p>]]></content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Creating a totally custom design for your publication Ghost comes with a beautiful default theme called Casper, which is designed to be a clean, readable publication layout and can be easily adapted for most purposes. However, Ghost can also be completely themed to suit your needs. Rather than just giving you a few basic settings which act as a poor proxy for code, we just let you write code. There are a huge range of both free and premium pre-built themes which you can get from the Ghost Theme Marketplace, or you can simply create your own from scratch. Anyone can write a completely custom Ghost theme, with just some solid knowledge of HTML and CSS Ghost themes are written with a templating language called handlebars, which has a bunch of dynamic helpers to insert your data into template files. Like , for example, outputs the name of the current author. The best way to learn how to write your own Ghost theme is to have a look at the source code for Casper, which is heavily commented and should give you a sense of how everything fits together. default.hbs is the main template file, all contexts will load inside this file unless specifically told to use a different template. post.hbs is the file used in the context of viewing a post. index.hbs is the file used in the context of viewing the home page. and so on We've got full and extensive theme documentation which outlines every template file, context and helper that you can use. If you want to chat with other people making Ghost themes to get any advice or help, there's also a #themes channel in our public Slack community which we always recommend joining!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Businessman &amp;amp; The Fisherman</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vindex/the-businessman-and-fisherman" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Businessman &amp;amp; The Fisherman" /><published>2014-08-12T11:18:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-08-12T11:18:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vindex/the-businessman-and-fisherman</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vindex/the-businessman-and-fisherman"><![CDATA[<p>An American businessman took a vacation to a small coastal Mexican village on doctor’s orders. Unable to sleep after an urgent phone call from the office the first morning, he walked out to the pier to clear his head. A small boat with just one fisherman had docked, and inside the boat were several large yellowfin tuna. The American complimented the Mexican on the quality of his fish.</p>

<p>“How long did it take you to catch them?” the American asked.</p>

<p>“Only a little while,” the Mexican replied in surprisingly good English.</p>

<p>“Why don’t you stay out longer and catch more fish?” the American then asked.</p>

<p>“I have enough to support my family and give a few to friends,” the Mexican said as he unloaded them into a basket.</p>

<p>“But… What do you do with the rest of your time?”</p>

<p>The Mexican looked up and smiled. “I sleep late, fish a little, play with my children, take a siesta with my wife, Julia, and stroll into the village each evening, where I sip wine and play guitar with my amigos. I have a full and busy life, señor.”</p>

<p>The American laughed and stood tall. “Sir, I’m a Harvard M.B.A. and can help you. You should spend more time fishing, and with the proceeds, buy a bigger boat. In no time, you could buy several boats with the increased haul. Eventually, you would have a fleet of fishing boats.”</p>

<p>He continued, “Instead of selling your catch to a middleman, you would sell directly to the consumers, eventually opening your own cannery. You would control the product, processing, and distribution. You would need to leave this small coastal fishing village, of course, and move to Mexico City, then to Los Angeles, and eventually to New York City, where you could run your expanded enterprise with proper management.</p>

<p>The Mexican fisherman asked, “But, señor, how long will all this take?”</p>

<p>To which the American replied, “15-20 years, 25 tops.”</p>

<p>“But what then, señor?”</p>

<p>The American laughed and said, “That’s the best part. When the time is right, you would announce an IPO and sell your company stock to the public and become very rich. You would make millions.”</p>

<p>“Millions señor? Then what?”</p>

<p>“Then you would retire and move to a small coastal fishing village, where you would sleep late, fish a little, play with your kids, take a siesta with your wife, and stroll in to the village in the evenings where you could sip wine and play your guitar with your amigos.”</p>

<p>Adapted from the “Anekdote zur Senkung der Arbeitsmoral” by <strong>Heinrich Böll</strong></p>

<p>An influential German write and Nobel Prize for Literature in 1972.</p>]]></content><author><name>Hannah Wolfe</name></author><category term="fables" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An American businessman took a vacation to a small coastal Mexican village on doctor’s orders. Unable to sleep after an urgent phone call from the office the first morning, he walked out to the pier to clear his head. A small boat with just one fisherman had docked, and inside the boat were several large yellowfin tuna. The American complimented the Mexican on the quality of his fish.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Full and Comprehensive Style Test</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vindex/a-full-and-comprehensive-style-test" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Full and Comprehensive Style Test" /><published>2012-09-01T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-01T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vindex/a-full-and-comprehensive-style-test</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vindex/a-full-and-comprehensive-style-test"><![CDATA[<p>Below is just about everything you’ll need to style in the theme. Check the source code to see the many embedded elements within paragraphs.</p>


<hr />

<h1 id="heading1">Heading 1</h1>

<h2 id="heading2">Heading 2</h2>

<h3 id="heading3">Heading 3</h3>

<h4 id="heading4">Heading 4</h4>

<h5 id="heading5">Heading 5</h5>

<h6 id="heading6">Heading 6</h6>

<hr />

<p>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, <a title="test link" href="#">test link</a> adipiscing elit. <strong>This is strong.</strong> Nullam dignissim convallis est. Quisque aliquam. <em>This is emphasized.</em> Donec faucibus. Nunc iaculis suscipit dui. 5<sup>3</sup> = 125. Water is H<sub>2</sub>O. Nam sit amet sem. Aliquam libero nisi, imperdiet at, tincidunt nec, gravida vehicula, nisl. <cite>The New York Times</cite> (That’s a citation). <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Underline.</span> Maecenas ornare tortor. Donec sed tellus eget sapien fringilla nonummy. Mauris a ante. Suspendisse quam sem, consequat at, commodo vitae, feugiat in, nunc. Morbi imperdiet augue quis tellus.</p>

<p><abbr title="Hyper Text Markup Language">HTML</abbr> and <abbr title="Cascading Style Sheets">CSS</abbr> are our tools. Mauris a ante. Suspendisse quam sem, consequat at, commodo vitae, feugiat in, nunc. Morbi imperdiet augue quis tellus.  Praesent mattis, massa quis luctus fermentum, turpis mi volutpat justo, eu volutpat enim diam eget metus. To copy a file type <code>COPY <var>filename</var></code>. <del>Dinner’s at 5:00.</del> <ins>Let’s make that 7.</ins> This <span style="text-decoration:line-through;">text</span> has been struck.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="media">Media</h2>

<p>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore.</p>

<h3 id="bigimage">Big Image</h3>

<p><img src="http://demo.ghost.io/content/images/2014/09/testimg1.jpeg" alt="Test Image" /></p>

<p>Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur.</p>

<h3 id="smallimage">Small Image</h3>

<p>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore.</p>

<p><img src="http://demo.ghost.io/content/images/2014/09/testimg2.jpg" alt="Small Test Image" /></p>

<p>Labore et dolore.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="listtypes">List Types</h2>

<h3 id="definitionlist">Definition List</h3>

<dl>
<dt>Definition List Title</dt>
<dd>This is a definition list division.</dd>
<dt>Definition</dt>
<dd>An exact statement or description of the nature, scope, or meaning of something: <em>our definition of what constitutes poetry.</em></dd>
</dl>

<h3 id="orderedlist">Ordered List</h3>

<ol>
<li>List Item 1  </li>
<li>List Item 2 <br />
<ol><li>Nested list item A</li>
<li>Nested list item B</li></ol></li>
<li>List Item 3</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="unorderedlist">Unordered List</h3>

<ul>
<li>List Item 1</li>
<li>List Item 2
<ul><li>Nested list item A</li>
<li>Nested list item B</li></ul></li>
<li>List Item 3</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="table">Table</h2>

<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<th>Table Header 1</th>
<th>Table Header 2</th>
<th>Table Header 3</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Division 1</td>
<td>Division 2</td>
<td>Division 3</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Division 1</td>
<td>Division 2</td>
<td>Division 3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Division 1</td>
<td>Division 2</td>
<td>Division 3</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<hr />

<h2 id="preformattedtext">Preformatted Text</h2>

<p>Typographically, preformatted text is not the same thing as code. Sometimes, a faithful execution of the text requires preformatted text that may not have anything to do with code. Most browsers use Courier and that’s a good default — with one slight adjustment, Courier 10 Pitch over regular Courier for Linux users.</p>

<h3 id="code">Code</h3>

<p>Code can be presented inline, like <code>&lt;?php bloginfo('stylesheet_url'); ?&gt;</code>, or within a <code>&lt;pre&gt;</code> block. Because we have more specific typographic needs for code, we’ll specify Consolas and Monaco ahead of the browser-defined monospace font.</p>

<p>Code blocks can also be inserted with the highlight tag as below:</p>
<pre>
    
    {% highlight language-x %}
    # some code
    {% endhighlight %}
    
</pre>

<p>More information about code highlighting in jekyll can be found  <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/templates/#code-snippet-highlighting">in Jekyll documentation</a>.</p>

<p>These area a couple of examples showing the resulting highlighted code:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-css" data-lang="css"><span class="c">/* css code sample */</span>
<span class="nf">#container</span> <span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="nl">float</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="nb">left</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="nl">margin</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="m">0</span> <span class="m">-240px</span> <span class="m">0</span> <span class="m">0</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="nl">width</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="m">100%</span><span class="p">;</span>
<span class="p">}</span></code></pre></figure>


<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><table class="rouge-table"><tbody><tr><td class="gutter gl"><pre class="lineno">1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="c1">// javascript code sample</span>
<span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">ajax</span><span class="p">({</span>
  <span class="na">type</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">POST</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
  <span class="na">url</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">backend.php</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
  <span class="na">data</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="dl">"</span><span class="s2">q=</span><span class="dl">"</span><span class="o">+</span><span class="nx">myform</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">serialize</span><span class="p">(),</span>
  <span class="na">success</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">data</span><span class="p">){</span>
    <span class="c1">// on success use return data here</span>
  <span class="p">},</span>
  <span class="na">error</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">xhr</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">type</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">exception</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="c1">// if ajax fails display error alert</span>
    <span class="nf">alert</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="dl">"</span><span class="s2">ajax error response type </span><span class="dl">"</span><span class="o">+</span><span class="nx">type</span><span class="p">);</span>
  <span class="p">}</span>
<span class="p">});</span>
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre></figure>

<p>Now you can also use <a href="https://highlightjs.org/">highlight.js</a>.
For more on how to use it and on the available styles check their
<a href="https://highlightjs.org/static/demo/">demo</a> and
<a href="http://highlightjs.readthedocs.org/en/latest/">documentation</a> pages.</p>

<div class="system">
<pre><code class="swift">// Swift code sample
import Foundation

@objc class Person: Entity {
  var name: String!
  var age:  Int!

  init(name: String, age: Int) {
    /* /* ... */ */
  }

  // Return a descriptive string for this person
  func description(offset: Int = 0) -> String {
    return "\(name) is \(age + offset) years old"
  }
}
</code></pre>
</div>


<hr />

<h2 id="blockquotes">Blockquotes</h2>

<p>Let’s keep it simple. Italics are good to help set it off from the body text. Be sure to style the citation.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. I am a HAL 9000 computer. I became operational at the H.A.L. plant in Urbana, Illinois on the 12th of January 1992. My instructor was Mr. Langley, and he taught me to sing a song. If you’d like to hear it I can sing it for you. <cite>— <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HAL_9000">HAL 9000</a></cite></p>
</blockquote>

<p>And here’s a bit of trailing text.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="textlevelsemantics">Text-level semantics</h2>

<p>The <a href="#">a element</a> example <br />
The <abbr>abbr element</abbr> and <abbr title="Title text">abbr element with title</abbr> examples <br />
The <b>b element</b> example <br />
The <cite>cite element</cite> example <br />
The <code>code element</code> example <br />
The <del>del element</del> example <br />
The <dfn>dfn element</dfn> and <dfn title="Title text">dfn element with title</dfn> examples <br />
The <em>em element</em> example <br />
The <i>i element</i> example <br />
The <ins>ins element</ins> example <br />
The <kbd>kbd element</kbd> example <br />
The <mark>mark element</mark> example <br />
The <q>q element <q>inside</q> a q element</q> example <br />
The <s>s element</s> example <br />
The <samp>samp element</samp> example <br />
The <small>small element</small> example <br />
The <span>span element</span> example <br />
The <strong>strong element</strong> example <br />
The <sub>sub element</sub> example <br />
The <sup>sup element</sup> example <br />
The <var>var element</var> example <br />
The <u>u element</u> example</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="forms">Forms</h2>

<form>
<fieldset>
<legend>Inputs as descendents of labels (form legend)</legend>
<label>
<b>Text input</b>
<input type="text" value="default value">
</label>
<label>
<b>Email input</b>
<input type="email">
</label>
<label>
<b>Search input</b>
<input type="search">
</label>
<label>
<b>Tel input</b>
<input type="tel">
</label>
<label>
<b>URL input</b>
<input type="url" placeholder="http://">
</label>
<label>
<b>Password input</b>
<input type="password" value="password">
</label>
<label>
<b>File input</b>
<input type="file">
</label>
<label>
<b>Radio input</b>
<input type="radio" name="rad">
</label>
<label>
<b>Checkbox input</b>
<input type="checkbox">
</label>
<label>
<input type="radio" name="rad"> Radio input
</label>
<label>
<input type="checkbox"> Checkbox input
</label>
<label>
<b>Select field</b>
<select>
<option>Option 01</option>
<option>Option 02</option>
</select>
</label>
<label>
<b>Textarea</b>
<textarea cols="30" rows="5" >Textarea text</textarea>
</label>
</fieldset>

<fieldset>
<legend>Clickable inputs and buttons</legend>
<input type="image" src="http://placekitten.com/90/24" alt="Image (input)">
<input type="reset" value="Reset (input)">
<input type="button" value="Button (input)">
<input type="submit" value="Submit (input)">
<button type="reset">Reset (button)</button>
<button type="button">Button (button)</button>
<button type="submit">Submit (button)</button>
</fieldset>

<fieldset id="boxsize">
<legend>box-sizing tests</legend>
<div><input type="text" value="text"></div>
<div><input type="email" value="email"></div>
<div><input type="search" value="search"></div>
<div><input type="url" value="http://example.com"></div>
<div><input type="password" value="password"></div>

<div><input type="color" value="#000000"></div>
<div><input type="number" value="5"></div>
<div><input type="range" value="10"></div>
<div><input type="date" value="1970-01-01"></div>
<div><input type="month" value="1970-01"></div>
<div><input type="week" value="1970-W01"></div>
<div><input type="time" value="18:23"></div>
<div><input type="datetime" value="1970-01-01T00:00:00Z"></div>
<div><input type="datetime-local" value="1970-01-01T00:00"></div>

<div><input type="radio"></div>
<div><input type="checkbox"></div>

<div><select><option>Option 01</option><option>Option 02</option></select></div>
<div><textarea cols="30" rows="5" >Textarea text</textarea></div>

<div><input type="image" src="http://placekitten.com/90/24" alt="Image (input)"></div>
<div><input type="reset" value="Reset (input)"></div>
<div><input type="button" value="Button (input)"></div>
<div><input type="submit" value="Submit (input)"></div>

<div><button type="reset">Reset (button)</button></div>
<div><button type="button">Button (button)</button></div>
<div><button type="submit">Submit (button)</button></div>
</fieldset>
</form>

<hr />

<h2 id="embeds">Embeds</h2>

<p>Sometimes all you want to do is embed a little love from another location and set your post alive.</p>

<h3 id="video">Video</h3>

<p>Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat.</p>

<iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/103224792?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>Culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.</p>

<h3 id="slides">Slides</h3>

<p>Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat.</p>

<script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="34d2856027ce01316b5d621ab8e7d421" data-ratio="1.33333333333333" src="//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"></script>

<p>Culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.</p>

<h3 id="audio">Audio</h3>

<p>Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat.</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/169381837&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;visual=true"></iframe>

<p>Culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.</p>

<h3 id="code">Code</h3>

<p>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt.</p>

<p><div data-height="268" data-theme-id="0" data-slug-hash="bcqhe" data-default-tab="js" data-user="rglazebrook" class='codepen'></p>

<pre><code>var c = new Sketch.create({autoclear: false}),
    bigCircle = 50,
    littleCircle = 5,
    // The velocity value determines how much to move the spinner head (in radians).
    velocity = 0.105,
    hue = 0,
    // The alpha value below determines the length of the spinner&#39;s tail.
    bg = &#39;rgba(40,40,40,.075)&#39;;
    Spinner = function() {};

Spinner.prototype.setup = function() {
  this.x = c.width / 2;
  this.y = c.height / 2 - bigCircle;
  this.rotation = 0;
}
Spinner.prototype.update = function() {
  this.rotation += velocity;
  this.rotation = this.rotation % TWO_PI;
  this.x = c.width /2 + cos(this.rotation) * bigCircle;
  this.y = c.height / 2 + sin(this.rotation) * bigCircle;
}
Spinner.prototype.draw = function() {
  c.fillStyle = &#39;hsl(&#39;+hue+&#39;,50%,50%)&#39;;
  c.beginPath();
  c.arc(this.x, this.y, littleCircle, 0, TWO_PI);
  c.fill();
  c.closePath();
}
c.setup = function() {
  spinner = new Spinner();
  spinner.setup();
}
c.update = function() {
  spinner.update();
  hue = ++hue % 360;
}
c.draw = function() {
  spinner.draw();
  c.fillStyle = bg;
  c.fillRect(0,0,c.width,c.height);
}
</code></pre>

<p>See the Pen <a href='http://codepen.io/rglazebrook/pen/bcqhe/'>Simple Rotating Spinner</a> by Rob Glazebrook (<a href='http://codepen.io/rglazebrook'>@rglazebrook</a>) on <a href='http://codepen.io'>CodePen</a>.</p>

<p></div><script async src="//codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"></script></p>

<p>Isn't it beautiful?</p>]]></content><author><name>John O&apos;Nolan</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Below is just about everything you’ll need to style in the theme. Check the source code to see the many embedded elements within paragraphs.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I Have a Dream</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vindex/i-have-a-dream" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Have a Dream" /><published>1963-08-28T11:18:00+01:00</published><updated>1963-08-28T11:18:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vindex/i-have-a-dream</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vindex/i-have-a-dream"><![CDATA[<p>I am happy to join with you today in what will go down in history as the greatest demonstration for freedom in the history of our nation.</p>

<p>Five score years ago, a great American, in whose symbolic shadow we stand today, signed the Emancipation Proclamation. This momentous decree came as a great beacon light of hope to millions of Negro slaves who had been seared in the flames of withering injustice. It came as a joyous daybreak to end the long night of their captivity.</p>

<p>But one hundred years later, the Negro still is not free. One hundred years later, the life of the Negro is still sadly crippled by the manacles of segregation and the chains of discrimination. One hundred years later, the Negro lives on a lonely island of poverty in the midst of a vast ocean of material prosperity. One hundred years later, the Negro is still languished in the corners of American society and finds himself an exile in his own land. And so we’ve come here today to dramatize a shameful condition.</p>

<p>In a sense we’ve come to our nation’s capital to cash a check. When the architects of our republic wrote the magnificent words of the Constitution and the Declaration of Independence, they were signing a promissory note to which every American was to fall heir. This note was a promise that all men, yes, black men as well as white men, would be guaranteed the “unalienable Rights” of “Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness.” It is obvious today that America has defaulted on this promissory note, insofar as her citizens of color are concerned. Instead of honoring this sacred obligation, America has given the Negro people a bad check, a check which has come back marked “insufficient funds.”</p>

<p>But we refuse to believe that the bank of justice is bankrupt. We refuse to believe that there are insufficient funds in the great vaults of opportunity of this nation. And so, we’ve come to cash this check, a check that will give us upon demand the riches of freedom and the security of justice.</p>

<p>We have also come to this hallowed spot to remind America of the fierce urgency of Now. This is no time to engage in the luxury of cooling off or to take the tranquilizing drug of gradualism. Now is the time to make real the promises of democracy. Now is the time to rise from the dark and desolate valley of segregation to the sunlit path of racial justice. Now is the time to lift our nation from the quicksands of racial injustice to the solid rock of brotherhood. Now is the time to make justice a reality for all of God’s children.</p>

<p>It would be fatal for the nation to overlook the urgency of the moment. This sweltering summer of the Negro’s legitimate discontent will not pass until there is an invigorating autumn of freedom and equality. Nineteen sixty-three is not an end, but a beginning. And those who hope that the Negro needed to blow off steam and will now be content will have a rude awakening if the nation returns to business as usual. And there will be neither rest nor tranquility in America until the Negro is granted his citizenship rights. The whirlwinds of revolt will continue to shake the foundations of our nation until the bright day of justice emerges.</p>

<p>But there is something that I must say to my people, who stand on the warm threshold which leads into the palace of justice: In the process of gaining our rightful place, we must not be guilty of wrongful deeds. Let us not seek to satisfy our thirst for freedom by drinking from the cup of bitterness and hatred. We must forever conduct our struggle on the high plane of dignity and discipline. We must not allow our creative protest to degenerate into physical violence. Again and again, we must rise to the majestic heights of meeting physical force with soul force.</p>

<p>The marvelous new militancy which has engulfed the Negro community must not lead us to a distrust of all white people, for many of our white brothers, as evidenced by their presence here today, have come to realize that their destiny is tied up with our destiny. And they have come to realize that their freedom is inextricably bound to our freedom.</p>

<p>We cannot walk alone.</p>

<p>And as we walk, we must make the pledge that we shall always march ahead.</p>

<p>We cannot turn back.</p>

<p>There are those who are asking the devotees of civil rights, “When will you be satisfied?” We can never be satisfied as long as the Negro is the victim of the unspeakable horrors of police brutality. We can never be satisfied as long as our bodies, heavy with the fatigue of travel, cannot gain lodging in the motels of the highways and the hotels of the cities. We cannot be satisfied as long as the negro’s basic mobility is from a smaller ghetto to a larger one. We can never be satisfied as long as our children are stripped of their self-hood and robbed of their dignity by signs stating: “For Whites Only.” We cannot be satisfied as long as a Negro in Mississippi cannot vote and a Negro in New York believes he has nothing for which to vote. No, no, we are not satisfied, and we will not be satisfied until “justice rolls down like waters, and righteousness like a mighty stream.”</p>

<p>I am not unmindful that some of you have come here out of great trials and tribulations. Some of you have come fresh from narrow jail cells. And some of you have come from areas where your quest – quest for freedom left you battered by the storms of persecution and staggered by the winds of police brutality. You have been the veterans of creative suffering. Continue to work with the faith that unearned suffering is redemptive. Go back to Mississippi, go back to Alabama, go back to South Carolina, go back to Georgia, go back to Louisiana, go back to the slums and ghettos of our northern cities, knowing that somehow this situation can and will be changed.</p>

<p>Let us not wallow in the valley of despair, I say to you today, my friends.</p>

<p>And so even though we face the difficulties of today and tomorrow, I still have a dream. It is a dream deeply rooted in the American dream.</p>

<p>I have a dream that one day this nation will rise up and live out the true meaning of its creed: “We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are created equal.”</p>

<p>I have a dream that one day on the red hills of Georgia, the sons of former slaves and the sons of former slave owners will be able to sit down together at the table of brotherhood.</p>

<p>I have a dream that one day even the state of Mississippi, a state sweltering with the heat of injustice, sweltering with the heat of oppression, will be transformed into an oasis of freedom and justice.</p>

<p>I have a dream that my four little children will one day live in a nation where they will not be judged by the color of their skin but by the content of their character.</p>

<p>I have a <strong>dream</strong> today!</p>

<p>I have a dream that one day, down in Alabama, with its vicious racists, with its governor having his lips dripping with the words of “interposition” and “nullification” – one day right there in Alabama little black boys and black girls will be able to join hands with little white boys and white girls as sisters and brothers.</p>

<p>I have a <strong>dream</strong> today!</p>

<p>I have a dream that one day every valley shall be exalted, and every hill and mountain shall be made low, the rough places will be made plain, and the crooked places will be made straight; “and the glory of the Lord shall be revealed and all flesh shall see it together.”</p>

<p>This is our hope, and this is the faith that I go back to the South with.</p>

<p>With this faith, we will be able to hew out of the mountain of despair a stone of hope. With this faith, we will be able to transform the jangling discords of our nation into a beautiful symphony of brotherhood. With this faith, we will be able to work together, to pray together, to struggle together, to go to jail together, to stand up for freedom together, knowing that we will be free one day.</p>

<p>And this will be the day – this will be the day when all of God’s children will be able to sing with new meaning:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>My country ‘tis of thee, sweet land of liberty, of thee I sing.</p>

  <p>Land where my fathers died, land of the Pilgrim’s pride,</p>

  <p>From every mountainside, let freedom ring!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>And if America is to be a great nation, this must become true.</p>

<p>And so let freedom ring from the prodigious hilltops of New Hampshire.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Let freedom ring from the mighty mountains of New York.</p>

  <p>Let freedom ring from the heightening Alleghenies of Pennsylvania.</p>

  <p>Let freedom ring from the snow-capped Rockies of Colorado.</p>

  <p>Let freedom ring from the curvaceous slopes of California.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>But not only that:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Let freedom ring from Stone Mountain of Georgia.</p>

  <p>Let freedom ring from Lookout Mountain of Tennessee.</p>

  <p>Let freedom ring from every hill and molehill of Mississippi.</p>

  <p>From every mountainside, let freedom ring.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>And when this happens, and when we allow freedom ring, when we let it ring from every village and every hamlet, from every state and every city, we will be able to speed up that day when all of God’s children, black men and white men, Jews and Gentiles, Protestants and Catholics, will be able to join hands and sing in the words of the old Negro spiritual:</p>

<p><em>Free at last! Free at last!</em></p>

<p><em>Thank God Almighty, we are free at last!</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Martin Luther King</name></author><category term="speeches" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am happy to join with you today in what will go down in history as the greatest demonstration for freedom in the history of our nation.]]></summary></entry></feed>