<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/vindex/tag/welcome/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/vindex/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2025-10-27T18:45:08+00:00</updated>
  <id>/vindex/tag/welcome/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Vindex Cycling Club | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Vindex Cycling Club</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Welcome to Vindex Cycling</title>
      <link href="/vindex/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Vindex Cycling" />
      <published>2025-10-27T10:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2025-10-27T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/vindex/welcome</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/vindex/welcome">&lt;h1 id=&quot;hey-welcome-to-vindex-cycling-️&quot;&gt;Hey! Welcome to &lt;strong&gt;Vindex Cycling&lt;/strong&gt; 🚴‍♂️&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re thrilled to have you on board!&lt;br /&gt;
Whether you’re here to explore routes, get gear insights, or connect with fellow riders, &lt;strong&gt;Vindex Cycling&lt;/strong&gt; is your new home on two wheels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that first rides matter — so we’ve set up some &lt;strong&gt;Getting Started&lt;/strong&gt; posts to help you roll smoothly into the Vindex community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-few-things-to-know-before-you-clip-in&quot;&gt;A few things to know before you clip in:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vindex Cycling is built by riders, for riders.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Our mission is to bring together cyclists who care about performance, community, and the freedom of the open road.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can shape your own experience here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From sharing ride reports and photos to exploring our latest training tips or gear reviews — you’re in control of your journey.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We love data as much as we love climbs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Expect insights, analysis, and resources to help you ride smarter — not just harder.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customization and contribution are encouraged.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Want to suggest a new feature or route? Join our Discord or drop us a message — we’re always open to ideas from the peloton.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to get the most from your &lt;strong&gt;Vindex profile&lt;/strong&gt; — upload your rides, share your setup, and track your progress.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discover &lt;strong&gt;featured routes&lt;/strong&gt; curated by the community, from iconic climbs to hidden gems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check out our &lt;strong&gt;Cycling Journal&lt;/strong&gt;, where we share stories, product insights, and updates from the Vindex team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vindex Cycling was founded by a small group of passionate riders who believe cycling is more than a sport — it’s a mindset.&lt;br /&gt;
Every post, route, and discussion here aims to celebrate that spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready to roll?&lt;br /&gt;
Start by exploring our &lt;a href=&quot;/journal&quot;&gt;Cycling Journal&lt;/a&gt; or join the &lt;a href=&quot;/community&quot;&gt;Community Hub&lt;/a&gt; to meet other riders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ride hard, stay kind, and welcome to the peloton.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
– The Vindex Team ❤️&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>vindexcycling</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Welcome" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Hey! Welcome to Vindex Cycling 🚴‍♂️</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
